(logo chimes)
- [Instructor] Our enemy is now set up
exactly the way that we want it to.
So now what we're gonna do is
we're actually going to create
a prefab of our enemy so that we
can use it over and over again
and we'll actually manage all
of these enemies through a spawn manager.
So in our assets folder if you right click
we'll create a new folder
and we'll call it prefabs where we keep
all of our prefabs.
We'll take our enemy in our hierarchy
and we'll drag and drop
it into our prefabs.
And in this case our enemy
basically has all the different components
that we need I don't think we're gonna
change it anymore so we can actually
just right click and delete it from
our project hierarchy.
Now what we're gonna do is
create a new spawn manager
in our hierarchy so we right click,
we're gonna create an empty object,
and then we're going to rename our game
object to be spawn manager.
We don't really need to reset its position
or anything like that just because
it's going to take in numbers
from our screen anyways.
In our assets folder we're
going to go into our scripts,
and create a new c-sharp
script for our spawn manager.
Make sure you drag and drop
that onto the spawn manager object.
Now if we open our spawn manager script
now we're going to need a reference
to our enemy prefabs so we'll create a
public game object
that way we can drag and drop it
from our prefabs folder into our editor.
We'll call it enemyPrefab
and then in our start method
we're just going to spawn our enemy
in random locations so since we have a
prefab we need to use
our instantiate method
so that we can create another instance,
or a clone of our enemy prefab.
We're going to need our enemy prefab
to actually create.
For now we'll just spawn this enemy
in a random coordinate.
So we'll just make a new vector three
and we'll just put it at zero, zero, six
and last but not least we're going to
position our prefab in
the right orientation
so we're going to use our enemy prefab,
get its transform,
and then make sure it's oriented right
so we're going to use the rotation
we set in the prefab.
So now when we save in Unity
we should magically see an enemy pop up
somewhere on this platform.
And there's no enemy.
Well if we look at the bottom
of Unity you can see
that we have an error.
In fact, you can actually click on
these errors and it will
open up our console window.
So whenever we see these errors
or these warnings they usually
pop up in the console
and then we can actually take our console,
if we click on the little tab
we can drag it into other places.
In this case I'll put it next to my scene
so now we can actually
see any error messages
that pop up when we play the game.
So the prefab has not been assigned.
So we can clear that,
so in our spawn manager, yes.
So we didn't drop our enemy
prefab into the variable.
Lets just make sure we drop that in
so there's a reference to that.
So now that our enemy
prefab has a reference
to our actual prefab,
when we press play we should
see our enemy pops up,
and then they bounce and then we'll see
if we can escape,
too fast and we both fall.
So what you're gonna do is
in your assets folder make sure you create
a prefabs folder,
take your enemy game object,
drag it into that prefabs folder
so we can create our own prefab.
You can then delete the
enemy from the scene
because I don't think
we'll need to change it.
Then you're going to right click
in the project hierarchy,
you're going to create an empty object,
rename that empty object
to be a spawn manager.
In your scripts folder,
create a spawn manger script,
make sure you add it as a component
onto the spawn manager.
And then in your spawn manager script
you're going to make sure you create
a reference to your enemy prefab.
Then we're going to
instantiate the enemy prefab
in our start method
and we're just going to put
it at a random position for now.
Make sure that it's rotated
in the right direction.
Then just make sure that you
drag the enemy prefab
into the enemy prefab slot
on the script so that way
there's a reference to it
and then test your game out.
Now it's your turn.
(logo chimes)